From pixel representations of table tennis in the 1970s to modern day cinematic storytelling, video games have evolved a lot and become more immersive.
从20世纪70年代以像素呈现的乒乓球游戏，到如今具有电影级叙事感的作品，电子游戏已经有了长足的发展，变得愈发沉浸式。
But it’s not just the graphics and gameplay mechanics that have changed – it has also opened up a range of career options, including that of professional gamer.
但发生改变的不只是游戏画面和玩法机制——这个行业还拓展出了一系列职业选择，职业电竞选手便是其中之一。
When gaming first started, those who loved video games and wanted to make a career out of them often ended up as developers, testers or coders.
在电子游戏发展初期，那些热爱游戏并想以此为业的人，大多最终成为了开发者、测试员或程序员。
While there were competitions, sometimes held worldwide, in which amateur gamers could win money or prizes, it wasn’t really considered a career path until the late 2000s, when live streaming really took off and gamers became celebrities.
当时虽然也有一些赛事，有些甚至是全球性的，业余玩家可以在这些比赛中赢得奖金或奖品，但直到21世纪末直播行业真正兴起、电竞选手跻身名人之列后，电竞才被正式视为一条职业道路。
With e-sports now an integral part of gaming, what does a professional gamer’s life look like?
如今电竞已经成为游戏行业不可或缺的一部分，那么职业电竞选手的日常生活是怎样的呢？
The key, according to many pro-gamers, is practice – the same with many sports.
许多职业选手表示，成功的关键在于训练——这和许多传统体育项目是一样的。
While choosing the best peripherals is important, such as the right controller or keyboard, most pro-gamers spend hours every day working out hacks to save time or improve their chances of winning.
挑选合适的外设固然重要，比如趁手的手柄或键盘，但大多数职业选手每天都会花费数小时钻研技巧，以此节省操作时间或提高获胜概率。
And it’s not just while playing games that they need to be active, but also in real life.
而且他们不仅需要在游戏中保持良好状态，在现实生活中也是如此。
Exercising and stretching is vital to avoid injuries to their backs and wrists and preventing eye fatigue from spending long hours staring at monitors by taking regular screen breaks.
规律锻炼和拉伸至关重要，能有效避免腰背和手腕受伤；同时，长时间盯着显示器容易造成眼疲劳，因此定期休息也必不可少。
But it’s not just the physical aspects that gamers need to be careful with.
但选手们需要注意的不只是身体层面的问题。
According to some experts, like Dr Phil Birch, while the physical demands of e-sports and traditional sports are very different, the psychological impacts can be similar: regulating emotions, dealing with pressure and big crowds, and overcoming injury are just some of the common factors.
菲尔·伯奇博士等专家表示，尽管电竞和传统体育对选手的体能要求大不相同，但二者带来的心理影响却有相似之处：情绪调节、应对压力和观赛的大批观众、克服伤病困扰，这些都是二者共通的挑战。
So, while the life of a pro-gamer may sound fun with lots of button bashing, just remember that it takes a lot of discipline and hard work to do it full-time.
因此，尽管职业电竞选手的生活听起来似乎充满乐趣，只需整日敲击按钮，但请记住，想要全职从事这份职业，需要极强的自律和不懈的努力。